Inventory of the Berkeley Family Papers, 1828-1865
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Berkeley Family Papers, 1828-1865.
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Mss. 39.2 B44
25 items.
Family correspondence of the Rev. Parke Farley Berkeley, an Episcopal minister, his sister, Ann Butler (Berkeley) Berkeley, and his wife Mary Eppes (Thweatt) Berkeley; and of Mary B. Thweatt.
Berkeley family.
Administrative Information
Restrictions on Access
Collection is open to all researchers.
Scope and Content Information
Family correspondence of the Rev. Parke Farley Berkeley, an Episcopal minister, his sister, Ann Butler (Berkeley) Berkeley, and his wife Mary Eppes (Thweatt) Berkeley; and of Mary B. Thweatt. Includes letters from Lewis Minor at Kenyon College, Gambier, Ohio.
Letter, 18 February 1835, details a stagecoach ride; letter, 21 December 1844, discusses agricultural meetings and the division and sale of slaves to settle an estate; and letter, 30 August 1862, written by Charles Middleton, describes and justifies his failed suicide attempt.
Arrangement
Collection is arranged chronologically.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Kenyon College--History.; Episcopal Church--Virginia-- Clergy.; Coaching--United States-- History--19th century.; Agriculture--Southern States--History--19th century.; Slavery-- Virginia--History--19th century.; Suicide--United States-- History.
Persons:
Berkeley, Parke Farley, 1808-1888.; Berkeley, Ann Butler Berkeley.; Berkeley, Mary Eppes Thweatt.; Minor, Lewis.; Middleton, Charles.; Berkeley family.
Components List
- Lewis W. Minor, at Gambier, [Ohio], to Parke Farley Berkeley, at Mont Pelier Post Office, Hanover County, Virginia, August 9th, 1828.
- [Lewis W. Minor] to his cousin, Ann [ ? ], August 15th, 1828., On same sheet as Lewis W. Minor to Parke Farley Berkeley, August 9th, 1828.
- L[ewis] W. Minor, at K[enyon] C[ollege], Gambier, [Ohio], to Parke Farley Berkeley, at Edgewood, near Mt. Pelier, Hanover County, Virginia, January 13, 1829.
- Ann B. Berkeley, at Edgewood, [Hanover County, Virginia], to Parke Farley Berkeley, at the Theological Seminary, near Alexandria, D.C., January 25th, 1831., Also includes typed transcript.
- Lucy Calthorpe Smith to [Parke Farley Berkeley]., On same sheet as Ann B. Berkeley to Parke Farley Berkeley, January 25th, 1831. Also includes typed transcript.
- Ellen [ ? ] to her cousin, Miss [ ? ] Thweatt, at Mantua, [Chesterfield County, Virginia], [1831?]
- [ ? ], at Solitude, to her cousin, Mary E. Thweatt, at Colesville Post Office, Chesterfield county, Virginia, September 25, 1833.
  Postmarked Memphis, Tennessee.
- Maria [ ? ], at Fox Harbour, to [Mary E.] Thweatt, at Colesville Post Office, Chesterfield [County], September 26, 1833.
  Postmarked Office Tavern, [Amelia County], Virginia.
- E[ ? ] A[ ? ], at Vaucluse, to Mary E. Thweatt, at Mantua, Chesterfield [County, Virginia], December 16th, 1833.
- E[ ? ] A[ ? ] to Mary E. Thweatt, at Colesville Post Office, Chesterfield County, Virginia, March 3d, 1834.
- L. Thweatt, at Eppington, to Rev. Park[e] F. Berkeley, at the Theological Siminary [Seminary], near Alexandria, D.C., March 8, 1834.
- [ ? ], to Winchester, to Rev. P. Farley Berkeley, at the Theological Seminary, near Alexandria, D.C., March 10, 1834.
- Maria [ ? ], at Sugar Tree Grove, to her cousin, [Mary E.] Thweatt, at Colesville Post Office, Chesterfield [County], Virginia, February 18th, 1835.
  Letter details a stagecoach ride. Postmarked Nashville, Tennessee.
- M. W. Spooner, at Baltimore, to Mary E. Thweatt, at Coles Ville Post Office, Chesterfield County, Virginia, September 4, 1835.
- Mat [ ? ], at Mill Brook, to her sister, Mary E. Thweatt, at Wilkinsonville Post Office, Chesterfield County, Virginia, September 1836.
- Carter Berkeley, at Edgewood, [Hanover County], to Rev. P. Farley Berkeley, at Wilkinsonville, Chesterfield County, Virginia, 25th September 1837.
- Carter Berkeley, at Edgewood, [Hanover County], to Rev. P. Farley Berkeley, at Wilkinsonville, Chesterfield County, Virginia, 22d March 1838.
- F. N. B[erkeley] to Mary [Berkeley]., On same sheet as Carter Berkeley to P. Farley Berkeley, 22d March 1838.
- Thomas Nelson, at Oakland, [Hanover County], to Rev. Parke Farley Berkeley, at Wilkinsonville Post Office, Chesterfield County, Virginia, Also includes typed transcript.
  Postmarked Taylorsville.
- Mary [Thweatt], at Mantua, [Chesterfield County], to Rev. P. F. Berkeley, at Alexandria, D.C., May 20th, 1841.
- L. H. Minor, at Edgewood, to Rev. P. Farley Berkeley, at Wilkinsonville, Chesterfield [County], March 27, 1843.
- Robert C. Berkeley, at Broomfield, Hanover [County], to Rev. Parke F. Berkeley, at Amelia Court House, 21st December 1844., Mutilated.
  Letter discusses agricultural meetings and the division and sale of slaves to settle an estate.
- C. F. M[ ? ], at White Sulphur Springs, [Greenbrier County], to her brother, Rev. Parke F. Berkeley, at Mantua, Chesterfield County, Virginia, July 25, 1858.
- Charles Middleton, at Wintapoke [Winterpock] Post Office, Chesterfield County, Virginia, to Rev. P. F. Berkeley, at Winterham Post Office, Amelia County, Virginia, 30th August 1862.
  Letter describes and justifies Charles Middleton's failed suicide attempt.
- E. G. L[acy], at The Refuge, to "my dear cousin," February 27, 1865.
- L. H. Minor to Rev. P. F. Berkeley, at Mantua, Wilkinsonville, Chesterfield County, n.d., Incomplete.
  Postmarked Hanover, Virginia, March 8th.